Hubungi

1000 N. 4th St MR 61 Fairfield, IA 52557 United States +1(641)781-0982 (Mobile) lamhot.id@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/lamhotsiagian (LinkedIn) lamhotjm.github.io (Personal)

Keahlian Teratas

Test Automation
Software Testing Life Cycle
Software Quality Assurance

Certifications

jQuery and AJAX for Beginners -The Definitive Guide Getting Started as a Web Developer Agile Testing

Programming Foundations: Software Testing/QA

Java Basics for Beginners

Publications

Otomatisasi Pengujian Perangkat Lunak (Software Testing Automation)

Lamhot Siagian

✓ Experienced Automation Test Engineer | ✓ Willing to relocate| ✓ Available for Full-Time W-2 Employment until June 2023 Fairfield, Iowa

Ringkasan

Software engineer in test with 5 years of experience in designing and executing automation and manual testing for banking, finance, and e-commerce industry. Expert-level skills in developing automation test using selenium Java/ruby/python with Cucumber, Appium Android/IOS, Rest-Assured for API, and performance test with JMeter. Hands-on build CI/CD infrastructure & Visualization using Kubernetes, Docker, Jenkins, Gitlab CI, GCP (Google Cloud Platform), and Grafana.

Languages: Java, Ruby, Python, Go

Unit Test: Mockito, Junit, Java Hamcrest, TestNG, Karma, Mocha,

Chai, Pytest, Nose

Mobile Test: Appium IOS/Android, UI Automator, Solenoid,

Genymotion, Simulator, Charles Proxy

API Test: Postman, Rest-Assured with Cucumber, Client-API Ruby,

Newman

Web Test: Selenium Java/ Ruby/ Python, Robot Framework,

Cucumber

Performance Test: JMeter, Locust, Siege, Sauce Lab

Test Methodologies: Test Plan, Test Strategy, Test case, Test

execution Report

CI/CD: SonarQube, JaCoCo Code Coverage, Docker, Kubernetes,

GCP, Jenkins, Gitlab CI, Travis, Circle

Pengalaman

Maharishi International University Graduate Teaching Assistant Oktober 2019 - April 2020 (7 bulan)

United States

I worked closely to help students during labs, project sessions, grading assignments, recording class attendance, and checking project delivery. I selected 4 times as a Teaching Assistant in four different courses block below:

Page 1 of 3

CS544 - Enterprise Architecture by Prof. Joseph Bruen

CS425 - Software Engineering by Prof. Obina Kalu

CS472 - Web Application Programming by Prof. Keith Levi. PhD

CS422 - Database Management Systems by Prof. Mrudula Mukadam

Bukalapak

Senior Software Development Engineer in Test November 2016 - September 2019 (2 tahun 11 bulan)

Greater Jakarta Area, Indonesia

- Implemented complex automation tests for API, web, Android, and iOS using cucumber Java and Ruby.
- Responsible for Automation framework enhancement and maintenance and adding new features to the framework.
- I am also Part of Core QA which will provide solutions to teams with innovative ideas implementation
- Implemented performance test using JMeter, Siege and executed on GCP cloud / Sauce Labs.
- Implemented and maintain CI/CD pipeline for microservices, regression testing, and integration testing using Gitlab CI, Jenkins, and Travis CI.
- Provided detailed walkthrough of test plans, test cases, and test report to project team.
- Contributed to team effectiveness and efficiency through mentoring new SDET, code review, and pair programming.
- Partnered with developers and test engineers to improve and automate test and release processes.
- Created guidelines for quality assurance, test scenario / gherkin standards, and automation code standards.
- Responsible for Continuous integration and dockerization of the testing solution.
- Responsible for maintaining detailed documentation of product and framework using confluence.
- Responsible for migrating existing Jenkins CI/CD pipeline to Github Action based CI/CD with Docker integrations.
- Responsible for daily execution test result analysis and maintenance .

Penerbit Deepublish
Book Author
September 2017 - Agustus 2018 (1 tahun)

Jakarta, Indonesia

Pengujian Perangkat Lunak: Software Test Automation : ISBN : 978-602-475-707-6

Funding Societies Software Development Engineer in Test April 2016 - November 2016 (8 bulan) Keppel Towers, Singapore

- Designed, wrote, and implemented test cases into automation frameworks.
- Identified areas where automation can be leveraged to increase coverage.
- Built and maintained tooling and test infrastructure.
- Maintained test result reporting and visualization using Grafana and InfluxDB.
- Coordinated closely with customer success and support teams to triage, track down, and prioritize client-reported issues, including root cause analysis on critical issues and incidents.
- Ran and revised smoke tests to ensure optimal post-production behavior and manual testing.

Kurio

Software Engineer Mei 2015 - April 2016 (1 tahun) Slipi, West Jakarta

- Developing robust rest API along with clean code principle using Spring MVC
- Designed and implemented JUnit testing, and set up continuous integration (CI).
- Implement messaging using RabbitQM, email system using AMQP, AOP, Batch, Spring Security, Spring Integration, JUnit, and MongoDB.
- Implement a few parts of the front end using Angular, Javascript, HTML5, CSS, Blade, and Ajax

Pendidikan

Maharishi International University

Master's degree, Computer Science · (2019 - 2022)

Universitas Bina Nusantara (Binus)
Bachelor's degree, Information Systems · (2016 - 2018)

Institut Teknologi Del Associate's degree, Computer Science · (2012 - 2015)